{"tossups": [{"question": "This country is believed to be the home of the Austronesian language family. Following the February 28th Incident, a period known as the \u201cWhite Terror\u201d suppressed political opposition in this country. The rebel Koxinga led a government from this present-day country, which was known during colonial times as (*) Formosa. After losing the Chinese Civil War, Chiang-Kai Shek fled to this island and set up a Kuomintang-led government. For 10 points, name this island country located off of the coast of China with capital Taipei.", "answer": "Taiwan [accept Republic of China; do NOT prompt or accept on \u201cPRC,\u201d \u201cPeople\u2019s Republic of China,\u201d or \u201cChina\u201d]", "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This opera is based off of a novella by Prosper M\u00e9rim\u00e9e. At one point in the story, the title character of that novella is fascinated by another character\u2019s repeating watch. The overture for this opera contains an excerpt of a major character\u2019s theme: \u201cVotre toast, je peux [puh] vous [vu] le rendre.\u201d That character is (*) Escamillo. Earlier in this opera, after cigarette girls emerge from a factory and banter with the young men in a crowd, the title character introduces herself while singing \u201cL\u2019amour est un oiseau rebelle.\u201d For 10 points, name this opera, composed by Georges Bizet, which follows the seduction of Don Jos\u00e9 by the title gypsy.", "answer": "Carmen", "subcategory": "Fine Arts Audiovisual", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This man names a constant that is defined as one over 67.8 kilometers per second per megaparsec, or 14.4 billion years. That constant differs from the age of the universe because of the nonlinear expansion of the universe, and it was derived from the (*) red shift of retreating galaxies, used to determine the expansion rate of the universe. This man names a telescope that was used to take NASA\u2019s Deep Field photo, which depicts more than three thousand galaxies. For 10 points, name this man whose eponymous telescope was launched aboard the space shuttle Discovery in 1990.", "answer": "Edwin Hubble", "subcategory": "Science Other", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "This work\u2019s protagonist finds a velvet-lined cigar case on the street after a party at the Vicomte\u2019s house and later feigns taking piano lessons from Mademoiselle Lempereur. At the end of this novel, the town chemist receives the Legion of Honour, while the protagonist\u2019s daughter is sent to work in a cotton mill. The title character\u2019s husband causes a gangrenous infection after attempting to cure (*) Hippolyte\u2019s case of clubfoot. The protagonist of this novel is ultimately driven into debt by the merchant Lheureux and eats arsenic. For 10 points, what Gustave Flaubert novel focuses on the wife of Charles and her affairs with Rodolphe and L\u00e9on?", "answer": "Madame Bovary", "subcategory": "Literature European", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The members of this musical group began their musical careers alongside Laurent Brancowitz, forming the group Darlin\u2019 in 1992. In a track on their most recent album, a man being interviewed informs the listener that \u201ceverybody calls me...\u201d the name of that track. This group composed the music for (*) Tron Legacy and has not gone on tour since 2007. F0r 10 points, name this French house music duo that released the album Discovery, and along with Pharrell Williams, are up all night to get lucky.", "answer": "Daft Punk", "category": "Trash"}, {"question": "A poet describes this entity as arriving \u201camong all that sound/ like a shoe with no foot in it.\u201d In another poem, this entity takes the form of a gentleman caller of whom the narrator says, \u201cWe slowly drove - (*) he knew no haste / And I had put away / My labor and my leisure too.\u201d In a poem by Rainer Maria Rilke, this entity is the title character who holds fate in his hands as the speaker lifts \u201cLife\u2019s red wine / to drink deep of the mystic shining cup.\u201d For 10 points, name this subject of many poems by Sylvia Plath and Emily Dickinson.", "answer": "Death", "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "In one anecdote recounted by Pliny, this figure takes one of the largest pearls in the world and dissolves it in a cup of vinegar before drinking it. This ruler\u2019s chief minister Pothinus usurped control of the throne and replaced (*) this ruler with the puppet ruler Ptolemy XIII. This ruler would return to power after having her sister Arsinoe killed on the steps of the Temple of Artemis, and she gave her country up to Roman rule in order to maintain it. For 10 points, name this Egyptian queen who famously had a relationship with Julius Caesar.", "answer": "Cleopatra VII Philopator", "subcategory": "History Classical", "category": "History"}, {"question": "The landscape in this painting\u2019s background was inspired by the Cap de Creus peninsula in Catalonia. The artist of this painting created a similar one in which the floor is entirely made out of bricks known as the (*) Disintegration of [this painting]. A \u201ccreature\u201d which resembles a human face can be seen in the center of this painting, while ants crawl on an orange pocket watch in its bottom-left corner. For 10 points, name this Salvador Dali painting which shows three deformed clocks.", "answer": "The Persistence of Memory", "subcategory": "Fine Arts Visual", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "These entities can be described as lentic, and one on Titan is known as Kraken Mare. Paternosters are a series of these things, which can be split into holomictic and meromictic varieties. Limnology is the study of these entities, and when glaciers form these entities they are known as (*) tarns. Retreating glaciers can form the kettle varieties of these entities. Oxbow types of these entities form when meanders in rivers get cut off from the main source. For 10 points, name these bodies of water that are larger than ponds and include examples like Michigan and Superior.", "answer": "Lake [accept Sea; prompt on \u201cOcean\u201d because of ambiguity in some clues]", "subcategory": "Science Other", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "The Cainites assert that this man\u2019s actions were sanctioned by his victim and intended to bring about salvation. This man\u2019s purported choice of seating during a Passover dinner helped establish thirteen as an unlucky number. The death of this man is recounted differently in (*) the Acts of the Apostles and Matthew, but both agree on his final resting place, Akeldama, or the Field of Blood. Because of his most famous action, this man\u2019s name is used by many languages as a synonym for traitor or betrayer. This Apostle was paid thirty silver coins for his aid rendered to the Sanhedrin. For 10 points, name this Apostle, who betrayed Jesus.", "answer": "Judas Iscariot", "category": "Religion"}, {"question": "Pilgrims flock to this body of water as part of Kumbh Mela. This body of water\u2019s wildlife includes the Gharial crocodile and the Rhesus Macaque. High pollution levels in this body of water have occurred partially because of the dumping of ashes at sites such as Haridwar and Rishikesh. Visitors to the city of (*) Varanasi often \u201ccleanse\u201d themselves by bathing in this body of water. This river meets with the Brahmaputra River to form the largest mangrove forest in the world, known as The Sundarbans. For 10 points, name this holiest river in India which empties into the Bay of Bengal.", "answer": "Ganges River [accept Ganga]", "category": "Geography"}, {"question": "One character in this novel is given a ten-dollar bill by Senator Byrd, shortly after taking her to the home of John Van Trompe. In this novel, Topsy steals a necklace from a character who later gives away locks of her own hair. Near the conclusion of this novel, George and Eliza arrive in Canada after escaping the (*) Shelby plantation. This novel, subtitled \u201cLife Among the Lowly,\u201d includes Eva St. Claire being saved from drowning and the title character\u2019s death at the hands of Simon Legree. For 10 points, name this novel about the title slave, written by Harriet Beecher Stowe.", "answer": "Uncle Tom\u2019s Cabin, or Life Among the Lowly", "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "In the first step of this process, phosphorylation converts phos\u00b7pho\u00b7fructo\u00b7kinase into two isomerases, di\u00b7hydroxy\u00b7acetone phosphate and glycer\u00b7aldehyde phosphate, more commonly known as G3P, which is created in the first five reactions of this process. In the second reaction within this process, four (*) ATP molecules and two water molecules are produced. Also known as the Embden-Meyerhof-Parnas pathway, for 10 points, name this anaerobic process that breaks down glucose into pyruvate, the first step of cellular respiration.", "answer": "Glycolysis [accept Embden-Meyerhof-Parnas pathway before mentioned]", "subcategory": "Science Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "During one election, this man\u2019s opponent accused him of providing prostitutes to the Czar while he served as Ambassador to Russia. This man is the only former president to become a member of the House of Representatives. As Secretary of State, this man drafted the Monroe Doctrine and signed a treaty with Luis (*) Onis that gave Florida to the U.S. This president made Henry Clay Secretary of State in the \u201ccorrupt bargain,\u201d which helped him win the Election of 1824 against Andrew Jackson. For 10 points, name this sixth president of the United States and son of a previous president.", "answer": "John Quincy Adams [prompt on \u201cAdams\u201d; do NOT prompt or accept on \u201cJohn Adams\u201d]", "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This work advocates the ostracism of artists who experiment with new forms of expression. One section of this work considers whether a just man would remain just had he no accountability in the story of the Ring of (*) Gyges. Another section of this work analogizes the concept of goodness to the sun, whose rays are necessary to illuminate the truth of the world. For 10 points, name this magnum opus of Plato that articulates a comprehensive political and metaphysical worldview.", "answer": "The Republic", "category": "Philosophy"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s Regensburg Lecture drew outcry in the Muslim world after being mistranslated as saying that Muhammad brought \u201cevil and inhuman\u201d things. Tariq Ali responded to that controversy by saying that \u201cThe (*) Bavarian [...] is a reactionary cleric.\u201d Other critics of this man attacked his lavish dress, for which he was known as \u201cthe pope of aesthetics,\u201d while others were upset by his conscription into Germany\u2019s military in World War II. For 10 points, name this German Pope, born Joseph Ratzinger, who succeeded John Paul II and whose 2013 resignation led to the election of Francis.", "answer": "Pope Benedict XVI [prompt on \u201cBenedict\u201d; accept Joseph Ratzinger before mentioned]", "subcategory": "History European", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This novel sees Zillah and Joseph serve in the home of the gloomy and morose protagonist, who is often called a gypsy because of his dark skin. In this novel, that protagonist returns with mysteriously acquired wealth and digs up his true love\u2019s grave so that he can see her one last time. (*) This novel, narrated by Nelly Dean and Mr. Lockwood, sees the protagonist marry Isabella to inherit Thrushcross Grange. For 10 points, name this novel which talks about Heathcliff\u2019s relationship with Catherine Earnshaw, the only novel by Emily Bront\u00eb.", "answer": "Wuthering Heights", "subcategory": "Literature British", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "These were first created when one of Amaterasu\u2019s attendants died, forcing Uzume to hang a necklace near Amaterasu\u2019s cave. In Chinese myth, these are dictated by Zhulong the Candle Dragon\u2019s breathing. The Kachinas in Hopi myth share the Blue Corn (*) Maiden to cause these, while Cherokee myth says that these are the result of the Pine tree\u2019s hospitality to Sparrow. In another myth, the consumption of pomegranate seeds in the Underworld explains these. For 10 points, name these natural phenomena that are explained by Hades\u2019 abduction of Persephone.", "answer": "Seasons [prompt on Winter or specific seasons]", "category": "Mythology"}, {"question": "This composer\u2019s Liebeslieder Waltzes are a collection of love songs in the L\u00e4ndler [Lend-ler] style for vocals and four hands piano based on Georg Friedrich Daumer\u2019s Polydora. Robert Schumann praised this composer in \u201cNew Paths,\u201d and he worked with both this composer and Albert Dietrich to write the F-A-E Sonata for Joseph Joachim [Wah-keem]. (*) As a balance to this composer\u2019s more cheerful piece that he wrote for the University of Breslau, he wrote his Tragic Overture. That more cheerful piece was his Academic Festival Overture. For 10 points, name this composer who wrote the Hungarian Dances and A German Requiem.", "answer": "Johannes Brahms", "subcategory": "Fine Arts Auditory", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "In gel electrophoresis, an ethidium salt of one of these elements is used as an intercalating agent. An element from this group is found in a compound with potassium in Lugol\u2019s solution. In one compound, an element from this group substitutes the hydrogens in hydrocarbons. That compound is used to treat the surfaces of (*) cookware and is called teflon. Another element from this group is used to treat drinking water and disinfect swimming pools and is also found in table salt. For 10 points, name this group of elements that includes fluorine and chlorine.", "answer": "Halogens [accept Group 17]", "subcategory": "Science Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "The Holy Trinity Church was built using funds made from the sale of this good. A \u201cgolden\u201d object made from this good names a chivalric order founded by Philip III, Duke of Burgundy. An English tax on this good was known as the \u201cGreat Custom,\u201d and William de la Pole was a notable trader of this good. Members of the Arte della Lana in Florence produced this good and primarily composed the participants of the (*) Ciompi Revolt. Flanders was most famous for producing this good, which it traded to England. For 10 points, name this good which is obtained from sheep.", "answer": "Wool [The unmentioned order is the Order of the Golden Fleece] Packet 1 \u2013 Bonuses", "subcategory": "History European", "category": "History"}], "bonuses": [{"leadin": "Violent anti-Sikh riots broke out in India in 1984. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Operation Blue Star", "Indira Gandhi [prompt on \u201cGandhi\u201d]", "Tigers"], "parts": ["This operation targeted Sikh secessionists in the Golden Temple. The Indian army has been accused of stealing religious relics during its execution.", "Operation Blue Star was ordered by this female prime minister of India. She is the daughter of Nehru and shares a last name with other another famous Indian leader.", "While Indira Gandhi was assassinated by her Sikh bodyguards, her son Rajiv died at the hand of a group known as the Tamil [this animal]. This animal is the national animal of India."], "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "The Lense-Thirring effect is a consequence of this theory. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["General Relativity [prompt on \u201cRelativity\u201d; do NOT accept \u201cSpecial Relativity\u201d]", "Albert Einstein", "Tensors"], "parts": ["Name this theory which combines geometry with gravity. Its field equations relate the curvature of spacetime to momentum and energy.", "This man published the theory of General Relativity. His namesake field equations relate the Ricci Curvature to the stress and energy.", "Einstein\u2019s field equations are written in terms of these constructs, which are the multidimensional equivalents of vectors and matrices. Examples include the Ricci and metric."], "subcategory": "Science Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points, name these gods of the underworld.", "answers_sanitized": ["Hades [do NOT accept or prompt on \u201cPluto\u201d]", "Hel", "Osiris"], "parts": ["This Greek god of the underworld used pomegranate seeds to help him kidnap Persephone and make her his bride.", "This Norse god of the underworld is the daughter of Loki and Angrboda. The four-eyed hound Garm guards the entrance into her realm.", "This Egyptian god of the underworld was the father of Horus, and he was chopped into many pieces by Set."], "category": "Mythology"}, {"leadin": "Most philosophers of the Middle Ages utilized a method of critical thought called Scholasticism. For 10 points each, answer these questions about Scholastic philosophers.", "answers_sanitized": ["Peter (or Pierre) Abelard", "St. Thomas Aquinas", "God"], "parts": ["This philosopher\u2019s most famous text, Sic et Non, translated from Medieval Latin as \u201cYes and No,\u201d addresses one hundred fifty-eight contradictions in Christian theology. He notably had an affair with Heloise.", "This other philosopher is best known for his Summa contra Gentiles and his Summa Theologica. He is also known as \u201cDoctor Angelicus\u201d and \u201cDoctor Communis.\u201d", "Proving the existence of this entity was the chief task of scholastic philosopher Anselm of Canterbury. Aquinas notably made five proofs for the existence of this figure."], "category": "Philosophy"}, {"leadin": "While riding on this object, one character exclaims \u201cIt\u2019s Malabar.\u201d For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Rocking Horse [prompt on partial answer]", "D.H. Lawrence", "Lady Chatterley\u2019s Lover"], "parts": ["Name this object that Paul rides in order to predict the winner of races. As a result of riding this object, Paul gains eighty thousand pounds for his mother.", "The rocking horse is from \u201cThe Rocking-Horse Winner,\u201d a story by this author who wrote about Paul Morel in Sons and Lovers.", "D.H. Lawrence also wrote this novel about the title character, Constance, and her affair with the gamekeeper Oliver Mellors."], "subcategory": "Literature British", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "This island was the site of the last amphibious landing during World War II. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Borneo", "Proboscis Monkey or Nasalis larvatus [prompt on partial answer]", "Tsunami"], "parts": ["Name this third largest island in the world, shared by Indonesia, Malaysia, and Brunei.", "Borneo\u2019s great biodiversity includes some odd species, such as these primates named for their long, pouch-like noses. Locals call them Orang Belanda because of their large bellies, a reference to the Dutch.", "In 2004, one of these events largely spared Borneo but severely damaged the western Indonesian islands. Up to two hundred eighty thousand people died as a result of this type of natural disaster that was precipitated by an earthquake."], "category": "Geography"}, {"leadin": "A work by this poet reads in its entirety, \u201cThe apparition of these faces in the crowd; \\ Petals on a wet, black bough.\u201d For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Ezra Pound", "\u201cThe Red Wheelbarrow\u201d", "William Carlos Williams"], "parts": ["Name this poet of \u201cIn a Station of the Metro,\u201d who was heavily inspired by East Asian poetry. This man also penned The Cantos, an epic poem in one hundred sixteen sections.", "This other short poem features the title object \u201cglazed with rain water / beside the white chickens.\u201d This poem was originally published without a title in the collection Spring and All.", "This American poet wrote \u201cThe Red Wheelbarrow.\u201d He also wrote an epic poem on a New Jersey city, \u201cPaterson.\u201d"], "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "This figure stares in shock while writing his namesake gospel, as an angel flies down in one work in the Contarelli Chapel. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["St. Matthew [accept Calling of St. Matthew or Inspiration of St. Matthew]", "Michelangelo Merisi da Caravaggio", "Chiaroscuro"], "parts": ["Name this Biblical figure. In another painting, scholars debate whether this figure is the old man pointing to himself or the tax collector counting coins.", "This artist painted the Calling of St. Matthew and the Inspiration of St. Matthew. This Baroque artist also painted a self-portrait of himself on the head of Goliath in a painting of David.", "Caravaggio often used tenebrism, which is a more pronounced version of this technique that contrasts the light and dark backgrounds of the setting."], "subcategory": "Fine Arts Visual", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "Senator Abraham Ribicoff accused this city\u2019s police of \u201cGestapo tactics.\u201d For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Chicago", "Hubert H. Humphrey", "Pig [accept Pigasus]"], "parts": ["Riots broke out in 1968 at the Democratic National Convention in this city, where Mayor Richard Daley was criticized for his police\u2019s use of excessive force on anti-Vietnam War protestors.", "Protesters were especially upset that this Vice President was nominated in lieu of a fellow Minnesotan, the more anti-war Eugene McCarthy, given that this man didn\u2019t compete in the primaries.", "In protest of the Democratic Party, the Youth International Party nominated this type of animal for President; the Chicago Seven\u2019s arrest interrupted their planned speech for this animal\u2019s candidacy."], "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "These organelles are reduced or not present in Zellweger Syndrome. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Peroxisome", "Catalase", "Amylase"], "parts": ["Name this organelle that uses enzymes to decompose its namesake compound into hydrogen and oxygen. It\u2019s also used to breakdown long chain fatty acids.", "This enzyme is used by peroxisomes to facilitate the transformation of hydrogen peroxide into water and oxygen.", "This other enzyme that is responsible for breaking down starches can be found in saliva."], "subcategory": "Science Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "This meeting declared Arianism a heresy. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["First Council of Nicea", "Constantine I [accept Constantine the Great; prompt on \u201cConstantine\u201d]", "Council of Ephesus"], "parts": ["Name this ecumenical council that took place in 325 A.D. It set the date for Easter and led to the creation of its namesake \u201ccreed,\u201d which states that Jesus himself was God.", "The First Council of Nicea was headed by this Roman Emperor. This emperor legalized Christianity in his domain with the Edict of Milan.", "This other ecumenical council, held in 431 A.D., reaffirmed the Nicene Creed and declared Nestorianism a heresy."], "subcategory": "History European", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "This composer based <em>Totentanz</em> on the Dies Irae theme. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Franz Liszt", "Hungarian Rhapsodies", "Alexander Borodin"], "parts": ["Name this Hungarian composer of the Mephisto Waltz and Transcendental Etudes.", "This set of nineteen works by Liszt was based off of Gypsy themes. The second of these works features a lassan section and a friska section.", "This composer and Russian member of \u201cThe Five\u201d wrote the opera Prince Igor and dedicated his piece In the Steppes of Central Asia to Liszt."], "subcategory": "Fine Arts Auditory", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "En garde! Name these novels about dashing heroes, damsels in distress, and dangerous sword fights. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Ivanhoe", "The Princess Bride", "Le Morte d\u2019Arthur [accept The Death of Arthur]"], "parts": ["The epitome of hypocrisy, Sir Brian de Bois-Guilbert promises never to love again before kidnapping Rebecca, whom he loves despite his virulent anti-Semitism in this romantic novel by Sir Walter Scott about the title Saxon knight.", "Before killing Rugen in a swordfight, a character says, \u201cYou killed my father. Prepare to die,\u201d in this fantasy romance about the loyal dreamboat Westley and his verbally abusive true love Buttercup.", "The title character\u2019s son impales himself on his father\u2019s spear in order to strike the fatal blow to his father\u2019s head in this Thomas Mallory work about a king who is carried back to the Isle of Avalon on a black barge after his death."], "subcategory": "Literature British", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points each, answer these questions about languages influenced by one another.", "answers_sanitized": ["C [do NOT accept or prompt on \u201cC++\u201d]", "Java [do NOT accept or prompt on \u201cJavascript\u201d]", "Bash or Bourne-again shell"], "parts": ["Identify this early language that was developed by Bell Labs and was named for a single letter. It was later incremented to its \u201c++\u201d form with the addition of object oriented paradigms.", "This language was developed by Sun Microsystems and later acquired by Oracle. It is similar to C but uses bytecode to run on any system without recompiling.", "This language runs the command line at the heart of most Unix systems. It was compromised by the shellshock exploit discovered in late 2014, which allowed anyone to run commands on vulnerable websites."], "subcategory": "Science Computer Science", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "Answer these questions about everyone\u2019s favorite detective-Sherlock Holmes. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Sir Arthur Conan Doyle", "Irene Adler [accept either underlined portion]", "A Study in Scarlet"], "parts": ["Sherlock Holmes and Doctor Watson are fictional characters created by this British author.", "This character first appeared in the short story \u201cA Scandal in Bohemia.\u201d She is often considered to be Holmes\u2019 romantic interest by fans, especially because Holmes keeps a photograph of her.", "Sherlock Holmes first appeared in print in this 1887 story, whose colorful title derives from what Holmes considers to be the constant presence of murder in all aspects of life."], "subcategory": "Literature British", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "The use of an exclamation point in this man\u2019s logo was likely inspired by campaign staffers who had worked for Lamar Alexander in 1996. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Jeb Bush [prompt on \u201cBush\u201d or \u201cJeb\u201d]", "Pitbull [accept Armando Christian Perez]", "Mexico"], "parts": ["Name this former Florida Governor, who frequently sparred with Donald Trump during his 2016 presidential bid. This man\u2019s brother and father previously served as President.", "Jeb Bush and this bald Cuban-American rapper teamed up to bid on the Miami Marlins in 2017. This man\u2019s record label derives its name from the Miami area code, reflecting his and Jeb\u2019s mutual home city.", "Columba Bush, Jeb\u2019s wife, hails from this country. They met while Jeb was building a school in this country\u2019s city of Le\u00f3n [lay-OAN]. The sale of \u201cguaca-bowles\u201d by Jeb\u2019s campaign reflected the traditions of this country that Columba introduced to him."], "category": "Current Events"}, {"leadin": "Islam is the fastest growing religion in the world. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Muhammad", "Ali ibn Abi Talib", "Aisha"], "parts": ["The Angel Jibreel revealed the world of God to this merchant of Mecca. Name this central prophet of Islam who was raised by his paternal uncle Abu Talib of the Banu Hashim clan.", "One of the prophet\u2019s closest supporters was this cousin who broke down the doors of Khaybar. Shia Muslims hold that this man ought to have been the first caliph after the death of Muhammad.", "This wife of Muhammad faced off against Ali at the Battle of the Camel following the death of Caliph Uthman. She was married off at the age of six, an act that critics of Islam unceasingly decry."], "category": "Religion"}, {"leadin": "Filles de Kilimanjaro infused electric guitars with this man\u2019s music. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Miles Davis", "Cool", "Herbie Hancock"], "parts": ["Name this jazz trumpeter who released the song \u201cSo What\u201d on the album Kind of Blue.", "Davis was credited with pioneering a type of jazz described by this adjective. He also released an album with Gerry Mulligan called Birth of the [this adjective].", "Miles Davis also worked with this man, who later worked with the Headhunters to release the song \u201cWatermelon Man\u201d on the album Takin\u2019 Off."], "category": "Trash"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points each, name these things about determining an object\u2019s age.", "answers_sanitized": ["Isotopes", "14 amu [accept Carbon-14]", "Atomic bombs [accept Nuclear bombs, Little Boy, Fat Man; do NOT accept or prompt on \u201cthermonuclear bombs\u201d or \u201cnuclear reactors\u201d]"], "parts": ["Carbon dating relies upon these entities, forms of an element that may have different numbers of neutrons.", "Typically, carbon has a mass of twelve amu, but carbon dating relies on the decay of the isotope of this mass.", "Isotopes such as cesium-137 and strontium-90 do not naturally occur, but appeared after 1945 because of the use of these devices."], "subcategory": "Science Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "One participant in this event failed to commit suicide when his cyanide pill didn\u2019t work. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Assassination of Archduke Franz Ferdinand [accept synonyms for \u201cassassination\u201d]", "Gavrilo Princip", "Black Hand [accept Unification of Death]"], "parts": ["Name this event during which Serbian nationalists tried to assassinate an Austro-Hungarian leader during his visit to Sarajevo.", "After several failed attempts to assassinate Franz Ferdinand, this nineteen year old eventually shot both Ferdinand and his wife, Sophie.", "The Serbian nationalists who assassinated the Archduke were all members of this terrorist organization. Their leader, Apis, organized the coup against King Alexander and Queen Draga of Yugoslavia."], "subcategory": "History European", "category": "History"}]}